# Filip Mareš

Mistrovská 170/18, Praha 10 mobile: +420 777 11 66 30 e-mail: maresf@gmail.com

linkedin: http://uk.linkedin.com/in/filipmares1 portfolio: http://www.filip-mares.co.uk/

date of birth: 13. 6. 1980 nationality: Czech marital status: Single

#### **Professional Profile**

Client-side web developer with a high level of industry knowledge and over 16 years experience in creating fast, standards-compliant, accessible websites and web applications using current best practises.

Interested in creating clean and highly maintainable code which works across all browsers and platforms.

#### **Team experiences**

Provided leadership to small teams, experienced in working with cross discipline Agile teams, also in the Scrum Master role.

#### Portfolio

Completed work for major clients across various sectors including British Telecom, Tesco, M&S, Sony, Unilever, Lloyds TSB, Oriflame, Barclays, Garanti Bank, DHL, Datart and Neoluxor.

#### Website life cycle knowledge

Experienced in every step of website life cycle (planning, analysis, wireframes, design, development, testing, release, maintenance).

#### Ongoing

Most recently focused on Front End performance optimization, mobile development, RWD and RESS. Passionate about learning new technologies and skills in order to keep up-to-date.

#### **Technical Skills**

OO JavaScript, jQuery, Ajax, JSON, HTML5, XML, XSLT, SVG, web accessibility, cross-browser compatibility, web performance, OO CSS, LESS, web typography, mobile web, RWD, RESS, unit testing, continuous integration, source control

#### Other

languages: native Czech, advanced English driving licence: Groups A and B, skilled

#### **Work Related Experience**

# **Internet Projekt, a.s.** (2012 - 2014)

Lead Front-End Developer in Internet agency

#### Responsibilities

- Web Development & standards establishment
- Team leading & Scrum Mastering
- Mobile development

#### Clients

Ministry of Finance of the Czech Republic, Senate of the Parliament of the Czech Republic, Oriflame

# Silkroute UK (2011)

# Front-End Developer in Worldwide provider of supply chain solutions

#### Responsibilities

- · Web Development
- Mobile Development
- Set-top Box Development

#### Clients

Tesco

# **LBi London** (2008 – 2011)

### Front-End Developer in Digital Media Agency

#### Responsibilities

- Web Development
- Web Content Accessibility & Cross Browser Compatibility
- · Front End Performance Optimisation

#### Clients

BT, Lloyds TSB, M&S, Unilever, Sony, Houses of Parliament, National Grid, Barclays, F1, Garanti Bank, Tourism Ireland, Barratt Homes

# Nantuko (2004 – 2008)

# Lead Front-End Developer in Creative Internet Agency

#### Responsibilities

- Team Coordination, work redistribution and review
- Web Analytics & Strategy, Search Engine Marketing (SEO, PPC advertising & CRO)
- · Web Development

#### Clients

Neoluxor On-line Bookstore, DHL, Danone, Iveco, KESA Electricals - Datart, Metropole Zlicin - Centre of Fashion and Entertainment

# **M.P. Media s.r.o.** (2001 – 2004)

# Senior Front-End Developer in Publishing Company

#### Responsibilities

- · Team Coordination, work redistribution and review
- Web Development

#### **Projects**

Internet projects supporting selling of magazines, Mobile content developing

# **Economy.cz** (1997 – 2001)

### Front-End Developer in Internet Services Company

### Responsibilities

- · Web Development
- · Graphic Design

#### Clients

Ministry of Foreign Affairs of the Czech Republic, Dräger Safety, Ranný Architects, Asiana Global Travel Service

### Education

# **Czech Technical University in Prague** (1999 - 2002)

Faculty of Electrical Engineering

3 years studies of Programing, Mathematics, Physics and others.

# Gymnázium U Libeňského zámku (1995 - 1999)

GCE level, Secondary school

Certificate of Information Technology, Mathematics, English, and Czech Language. General studies focused on Information Technology and Mathematics.